A Guide to the Papers of William B. Spong, 1965-1974
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- General
  - 1972 Campaign Files
    - State Politics - Elections - Gubernatorial 1968-1969, 3 folders (Box 161)
    - State Politics - Jefferson/Jackson Day Dinner 1968-1972 (Box 161)
    - State Politics - Replies to Senator's Letters 1972 (Box 161)
    - State Politics - Spong Campaigns 1967 (Box 161)
    - State Politics - Waynesboro Meeting 1970 (Box 161)
    - State Politics - Waynesboro Meeting - Questionnaire 1970, 2 folders (Box 161)
    - State Politics - Young Democrats 1967-1971 (Box 161)
    - VIP Correspondence - Cabinet & Other Executive Branch Positions, including: Helen Delich Bentley (Federal Maritime Commission); Wilbur J. Cohen (HEW); W.J. Driver (VA); Don F. Eisele (NASA astronaut); Orville L. Freeman (Agriculture); George B. Hartzog (NPS, Interior); J. Edgar Hoover (FBI); E.A. Jaenke (Gov. Farm Credit Administration); W.P. Kelly (Job Corps, OEO); Robert L. Kunzig (GSA); Leonard H. Marks (US Information Agency); Lawrence F. O'Brien (Postmaster General); James B. Rhoads (Archivist of the US); Frank Sanders (Assistant Sec. of Navy); Robert Sargent Shriver, Jr. (OEO); Maurice Stans (Commerce); Dr. Floyd L. Thompson (NASA); Stewart L. Udall (Interior); Jack Vaughn (Peace Corps); John A. Volpe (Transportation); John W. Warner (Navy) 1967-1972 (Box 162)
    - VIP Correspondence - College Presidents & Chancellors, including: Dr. Conwell A. Anderson (Averett College); Dr. C. Ralph Arthur (Ferrum Junior College); Dr. James L. Bugg, Jr. (Old Dominion University); T. Marshall Hahn, Jr. (VPI); Dr. Harold H. Hopper (Virginia Western Community College); Dr. Taylor Reveley (Hampden-Sydney College); Wendell P. Russel (Virginia State College); Edgar F. Shannon, Jr. (UVA); J.C. Smiddy (Clinch Valley College); Dr. Lorin A. Thompson (George Mason College); Floyd V. Turner (Virginia Intermont College) 1967-1972 (Box 162)
    - VIP Correspondence - Embassies & Foreign Service 1968-1972 (Box 162)
    - VIP Correspondence - Governors & Lt. Governors, including: Tim Babcock (Montana); Colgate Darden, Jr. (VA); Mills E. Godwin, Jr. (VA); Linwood Holton (VA); Henry E. Howell, Jr. (VA); Fred G. Pollard (VA); Raymond P. Shafer (Pennsylvania); Thomas B. Stanley (VA); Jack Williams (Arizona) 1968-1972 (Box 162)
    - VIP Correspondence - Judges & Justice, including: R. Winston Bain; A.C. Buchanan; John W. Eggleston; Ernest C. Friesen, Jr. (Administrative Office of the US Courts); John R. Hess; Major M. Hillard; Robert J. Kelleher; John Wingo Knowles; John A. MacKenzie; C.H. Shield, Jr.; Alfred W. Whitehurst 1967-1972 (Box 162)
    - VIP Correspondence - Military, including: Jamie Adair (USN): E.C. Allen (USCG); John R. Blandford; J.A. Brown (USN); Arleigh Burke (Center for Strategic & International Studies); L.F. Chapman, Jr. (USMC); Bruce C. Clark (USA); J.C. Dempsey (USN); George Dufek (USN); A.B. Engel (USCG); George D. Eastes (USA); A.R. Gralla (USN); I.F. Haddock (USN): Means Johnston, Jr. (USN); Randolph W. King (Commander Norfolk Naval Shipyard); D.C. Lyndon (USNR); William J. McCaddin (Virginia National Guard); James W. O'Grady (USN); E.R. Reid, Jr. (USN); H.G. Rickover (USN); C.O. Triebel (USN); O.D. Waters, Jr. (USN); W.C. Westmoreland (USA) 1967-1972 (Box 162)
    - VIP Correspondence - Miscellaneous, including: Hudson T. Armerding (National Association of Evangelicals); Robert S. Bilheimer (National Council of the Churches of Christ); Lewis D. Crenshaw (UVA): Lewis Glasner (quill pen maker); Arthur Godfrey; Billy Graham; Dumas Malone; James J. Needham (NY Stock Exchange); J. Milton Patrick (The American Legion); Robert Porterfield (Barter Theatre); S. Dillon Ripley (Smithsonian); Pat Robertson (CBN); James Roosevelt (1969 Jan 7); Frank Stanton (CBS); John Walker (National Gallery of Art) 1967-1971 (Box 162)
    - VIP Correspondence - Political, including: Lincoln Alexander; Robert Andras; John M. Bailey; William C. Battle; FitzGerald Bemiss; Armistead L. Boothe; Herbert E. Gray (M.P. Canada); Andrew P. Miller; Lawrence F. O'Brien; Joseph E. O'Neil; William V. Rawlings 1967-1971 (Box 162)
    - VIP Correspondence - Presidents, Vice-Presidents, and White House Assistants, including: Bryce N. Harlow (Assistant); Hubert H. Humphrey; Lyndon B. Johnson; Mike Manatos (Assistant); Richard M. Nixon 1967-1971 (Box 162)
    - VIP Correspondence - Publishers & Editors, including: Robert A. Burnett ( Better Homes & Gardens); Cass Canfield ( Harper & Row); Sarah G. Carlin ( The Alexandria Gazette); Virginius Dabney ( Richmond Times Dispatch); John Eisenhard ( The Fauquier Democrat); Paul Gottlieg ( American Heritage); Melville Bell Grosvenor ( National Geographic Society); Henry Grunwald ( Time); Charles L. Gould ( San Francisco Examiner); Charence B. Hanson, Jr. ( The Birmingham News); Randolph A. Hearst; Andrew Heiskell ( Time); Robert E. Hood ( Boys' Life); Larry H. Israel ( Post- Newsweek Stations); Shields Johnson ( The Roanoke Times); William F. Knowland ( Oakland Tribune); Hobart Lewis ( Readers' Digest); Herman J. Obermayer ( Northern Virginia Sun); James Parton ( American Heritage); William D. Patterson ( Saturday Review); Gerald Piel ( Scientific American); Eugene C. Pulliam ( The Indianapolis Star and News); Charles C. Randolph ( Business Week); C.H. Rieley ( The Herald Publishing Corporation); Thomas R. Shepard, Jr. ( Look); James R. Shepley ( Time); F. Randall Smith ( National Journal); Louis Spilman ( News-Virginian); Charles E. Swanson ( Encyclopedia Britannica); Putney Westerfield ( Fortune Magazine) 1967-1972 (Box 162)
    - VIP Correspondence - United States House of Representatives, including: Frank Annunzio; John M. Ashbrook; Hugh L. Carey; W.C. (Dan) Daniel; Thomas N. Downing; T.J. Dulski; Florence P. Dwyer; Richard Fulton; Cornelius E. Gallagher; Robert N. Giaimo; Henry B. Gonzalez; Charles S. Gubser; Ken Hechler; Ed Jones; Cecil R. King; Dan Kuykendall; William M. McCulloch; John O. Marsh, Jr.; Carl D. Perkins; Fred B. Rooney; Dan Rostenkowski; Charles W. Sandman, Jr.; Herman T. Schneebeli; Frank Thompson; William M. Tuck; Lionel Van Deerlin; Gus Vatron; William C. Wampler; John H. Ware; G. William Whitehurst; Jamie L. Whitten 1967-1972 (Box 162)
    - VIP Correspondence - United States Senate(4 folders), including: James B. Allen; Birch Bayh; Henry Bellmon; Wallace F. Bennett; Edward W. Brooke; Quentin N. Burdick; Robert C. Byrd; Howard M. Cannon; Frank Church; Alan Cranston; Everett McKinley Dirksen; Thomas J. Dodd; Bob Dole; Thomas F. Eagleton; James O. Eastland; The Reverend Edward L.R. Elson, Chaplain; Paul J. Fannin; Hirem L. Fong; Barry Goldwater; Albert Gore; Mike Gravel; Robert P. Griffen; Edward J. Gurney; Clifford P. Hansen; Vance Hartke; Mark O. Hatfield; Spessard L. Holland; Ernest F. Hollings; Harold E. Hughes; Daniel K. Inouye; B. Everett Jordan; Len B. Jordan; Edward M. Kennedy; Edward V. Long; John L. McClellan; Gale McGee; George McGovern; Thomas J. McIntryre; Joan Mondale; Lee Metcalf; Jack Miller; Frank E. Moss; Karl E. Mundt; George Murphy; Edmund S. Muskie; Gaylord Nelson; Claiborne Pell; Charles H. Percy; Winston Prouty; William Proxmire; Jennings Randolph; William V. Roth, Jr.; Richard B. [Russell?]; Richard S. Schweiker; Hugh Scott; John Sparkman; Ted Stevens; Stuart Symington; Herman E. Talmadge; Strom Thurmond; Joseph D. Tydings; Francis R. Valeo (Secretary of the Senate); Lowell P. Weicker, Jr.; Harrison A. Williams, Jr.; Ralph W. Yarborough 1967-1972 (Box 162)
    - VIP Correspondence - Virginia Commonwealth Officials, including: Gerald L. Baliles; R.E. Booker; Joseph H. Campbell; S. Mason Carbaugh; Dr. Arthur Centor; Stuart W. Connock; Elbert Cox; Dr. R.M. Cox; Thomas P. Credle; C.P. Deane; Howard H. Gordon; L. Stanley Hardaway; William L. Heartwell, Jr.; H. Lester Hooker; T.J. Markow; James W. Moody, Jr.; G. Lloyd Nunnally; W.L. Painter; Walter W. Regirer; Maurice B. Rowe; Don W. Russell; T. Edward Temple; Anthony F. Troy; J. Van Schreeven; Charles D. Wilson 1967-1972 (Box 162)
    - VIP Correspondence - Virginia General Assembly, including: George A. Allen, Jr.; Hunter B. Andrews; Richard M. Bagley; Lloyd C. Bird; FitzGerald Bemiss; D. Woodrow Bird; Edward L. Breeden; Junie L. Bradshaw; Edward T. Caton, III; John Warren Cooke; Alan A. Diamonstein; Walther B. Fidler; Robert C. Fitzgerald; Tom Frost; Duncan C. Gibb; Virgil H. Goode; William H. Hodges; George J. Kostel; Lewis A. McMurran, Jr.; Thomas R. McNamara; C. Harrison Mann, Jr.; Mrs. Mary A. Marshall; J. Harry Michael, Jr.; Willard J. Moody; C. Armonde Paxson; Sam E. Pope; J. Sargeant Reynolds; W. Roy Smith; James M. Thomson; Stanley C. Walker 1967-1971 (Box 162)
- Daily Carbons ("Yellows")
  - Daily Carbons - "A" 1967-1970 (Box 162)
  - Daily Carbons - "Ba-Boz" 1967-1970 (Box 163)
  - Daily Carbons - "Bra-Chel" 1967-1970 (Box 164)
  - 1967-1970, Daily Carbons - "Chem-Cz" (Box 165)
  - Daily Carbons - "Da-Dy" 1967-1970 (Box 166)
  - Daily Carbons - "E-F" 1967-1970 (Box 167)
  - Daily Carbons - "G-Hamiton" 1967-1970 (Box 168)
  - Daily Carbons - "Hame-Hor" 1967-1970 (Box 169)
  - Daily Carbons - "Hos-Key" 1967-1970 (Box 170)
  - Daily Carbons - "Kia-Ly" 1967-1970 (Box 171)
  - Daily Carbons - "Ma-Mic" 1967-1970 (Box 172)
  - Daily Carbons - "Mid-Oz" 1967-1970 (Box 173)
  - Daily Carbons - "P-Reed" 1967-1970 (Box 174)
  - Daily Carbons - "Ree-Shea" 1967-1970 (Box 175)
  - Daily Carbons - "Shec-Suz" 1967-1970 (Box 176)
  - Daily Carbons - "Swa-Web" 1967-1970 (Box 177)
  - Daily Carbons - "Webb-Zy" 1967-1970 (Box 178)
  - Daily Carbons - "A-Carle" 1971 (Box 179)
  - Daily Carbons - "Carli-Fit" 1971 (Box 180)
  - Daily Carbons - "Fiv-Iz" 1971 (Box 181)
  - Daily Carbons - "Ja-Miller" 1971 (Box 182)
  - Daily Carbons - "Miller-Schneider" 1971 (Box 183)
  - Daily Carbons - "Schoa-Wiz" 1971 (Box 184)
  - Daily Carbons - "Woa-Z" 1971 (Box 185)
  - Daily Carbons - "A-Bly" 1972 (Box 185)
  - Daily Carbons - "Blum-Conn" 1972 (Box 186)
  - Daily Carbons - "Conr-Ez" 1972 (Box 187)
  - Daily Carbons - "Fa-Hep" 1972 (Box 188)
  - Daily Carbons - "Hera-Ky" 1972 (Box 189)
  - Daily Carbons - "La-Moo" 1972 (Box 190)
  - Daily Carbons - "Moore-Q" 1972 (Box 191)
  - Daily Carbons - "R-Shy" 1972 (Box 192)
  - Daily Carbons - "Sia-V" 1972 (Box 193)
  - Daily Carbons - "W" 1972 (Box 194)
- Miscellaneous Material
  - Index to Senator Spong's Speeches & Statements 1967-1972, 5 x 8 card file (Box 195)
  - Index to Legislation & Amendments introduced into Congress during 1974-1976 1974-1976 (Box 196)
  - Photographs of the Campaign for U.S. Senate 1966, 20 sheets (Oversize Q-12)
  - Posters of the Campaign for Re-election 1972, 2 items (Oversize Q-12)
  - Commonwealth of Virginia General Assembly Senate Joint Resolution No. 48 re American POWs 1970 (Oversize Q-12)
  - Poster for the William Randolph Hearst Foundation United States Senate Youth Program 1972 (Oversize Q-12)
  - Citation from AMVETS to Senator Spong 1969 (Oversize Q-12)
  - Certificate of Appreciation for Spong from the Oyster Bowl Committee 1969 (Oversize Q-12)
  - Audio and Video Tapes
    - 5 Video Tape Recordings of "Spong Statewide," TideWATR Productions, WTAR -TV, Norfolk, Virginia 1966 Nov 1
    - Radio Address by William Spong, Jr., Byrd-Spong Campaign Committee (4:43 minutes) 1966 Nov 3
    - WMAL-TV Close-up of Senator Spong 1967 Jan 6, 2 copies
    - Bob Jackson Interview with Senator Spong, with 4 cuts, "Accomplishments of the 1st session of the 90th Congress"; Main Issues next session"; "the war and 1968 elections"; "Personal reflections on first year in Congress" 1967 Dec 14
    - "The Man Himself Senator Spong" 1967 Oct 18
    - WRGM Interview 1968 Jan
    - International Assembly, Williamsburg, Virginia, Parts 1 & 2 1968 Jun
    - ABC Telephone Mid-East Interview 1969 Feb 20
    - WKBY - TV Tape of Bill Spong for Joseph Motley Whitehead, Hargrave Military Academy, Chatham, Virginia 1969 Apr 26
    - WGMS "Salute to the States - Virginia" 1971 Aug 17
    - WRC-AM/FM Radio spot by Senator William Spong re use of laundry soap as opposed to phosphate detergents, based on a report of the hearings conducted re this problem and chaired by Spong 1971 Dec 29
    - "Floater #1" and "Floater #2 n.d.
    - Legislative - Labor and Public Welfare - Health- Hunger Tour (Con) tape recording n.d.